Guide to the Henry Guerlac papers, 1922-1981
Guerlac, Henry papers, 1922-1981
- Series XXXII: Chronological correspondence: 1940-1975
  - McGraw Hill Encyclopedia (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Dictionary of History of Ideas (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Messenger Lectureship, (Dr. O. Temkin), 1970 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - American Historical Association (E. Lurie), Dec. 1968 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Humanities at Cornell, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Norwood Russell Hanson, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Carlson at Medical School, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Forman, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 18-21)
  - Provine (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 23-25)
  - Journal of History of Ideas, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Dix-huitième siècle, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Académie Internationale d'Histoire, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Ravetz - Copernicus Project, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 30-32)
  - Bells Case (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 34-35)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Martinique Illness (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Dexter Award, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 40-41)
  - Times Literary Supplement article, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 44)
- Series XXXIII: Correspondence, 1946-1956
  - A, 1949-1953 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - B, 1947-1953 (Box 29, Folder 46)
  - C, 1949-1953 (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - D, 1947-1952 (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - E, 1948-1953 (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - F, 1948-1953 (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - G, 1948-1953 (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - H, 1947-1953 (Box 29, Folder 52)
  - I-J, 1946-1953 (Box 29, Folder 53)
  - K-L, 1948-1953 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - M, 1947-1953 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - N-O, 1946-1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - P, 1948-1953 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - S, 1948-1953 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - T, 1949-1953 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Q-R, 1949-1953 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - U-W, 1947-1956 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - X-Z, 1948-1953 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Series XXXIV: Correspondence 1957-1963
  - C, 1960-1963 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - E, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - F, 1958-1963 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - G, 1957-1963 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - H, 1960-1963 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - J, 1960-1963 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - K, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - L, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - M, 1960-1963 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - N, 1960-1963 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - O, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - P, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - R, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - S, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - T, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - V, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - W-Y, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 26)
- Series XXXV: Guerlac and Cornell
  - Faculty Problems, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Ad Hoc Library Committee, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Cornell Scientists Association (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Committees and Chores, 1947-1972 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1949-1953 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Committee of Educational Policy, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Iowa Talk: "History of Science for Engineers at Cornell", 1956 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence pertaining to New York State Association of European Historians Meeting, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - Dean's Committee on the Humanities, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 35-37)
  - Dean's Committee on the Humanities - Data and Reports, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - Dean's Committee on Humanities - Possible Consultant, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Sub-committee of Humanities Council (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - Jacob Lorch, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 41)
  - Movies for Teaching (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - Ithaca College Lecture, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 43)
  - Society for the History of Technology, 1958-1960 (Box 30, Folder 44)
  - Faculty Sub-committee on Science, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - Rossiter Committee, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - History, Philosophy and Sociology of Science at Cornell, 1952-1960 (Box 30, Folder 47-48)
  - Pre-departure Orientation Course, Paris, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - Community Chest, 1951-1952 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Publishers - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Minimal Technical Knowledge for Graduate Students (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Graduate School General Committee, etc., 1949-1951 (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
  - Graduate School, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Centennial, 1960-1964 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Collegium Plan and Professor-at-large, 1963-1965 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Phillips Wyman Memorial Fund, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Isis (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Statler Club, 1959-1963 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Summer Ithaca - Ithaca Festival, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 12-18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1965 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Journal of the History of Ideas, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - McGraw-Hill, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1946-1952 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Courses and New Courses, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - National Science Foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Bulletins, 1941-1950 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Material on Oppenheimer (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence re Radar and Patents (Box 31, Folder 29-31)
  - Personal Journal and Diary, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - History of the Radiation Laboratory, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Patents, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1949-1953 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Hopkins Symposium, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Academie Internationale, 1952-1953 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - Union Internationale, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 38-39)
  - Work to be Done, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - Early British Radar (Box 31, Folder 41-42)
  - Steering Committee on Post-war Scientific Research, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 43)
  - Programme de la Rue Cadet (Box 31, Folder 44)
  - Photographs and Negatives (originally followed correspondence), 1969 (Box 31, Folder 45)
  - Diploma: Cornell University Master of Science, 1933 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Guerlac to Mrs. M.C. Jacobs, Feb. 16, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 46)
  - Cornell University - personal, 1945-1946 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University - memorabilia, 1925-1929 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Sigma Xi; Marine Biological Lab (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Music, 1932-1937 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - MIT plan and proposals (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - International History of Science Congress, 1955-1962 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Harvard - Langer course and seminar (Box 32, Folder 9-10)
  - Medieval history (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Le Temps, Mar. 1912 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - France 1940-1942: A Collection of Documents and Bibliography (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Les Lois de l'Occupation en France (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Harvard - American Defense Group (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - WRUL Radio Boston, 1939-1942 (Box 32, Folder 16-17)
  - Reprints - requests (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Studies in Romanticism - David Bonnell Green (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - History of Quantification Conference (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Reviews and papers (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - "The Origins and Early Development of the Commune of Amiens" (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Society for the Humanities 101 - Fall, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Society for the Humanities 101 - Fall, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Syllabus: History 165-166 "Science in Western Civilization", 1950 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - "Science in Western Civilization - a Syllabus", 1951 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - History 165 - "Science in Western Civilization" - first semester, Vol. I, 1958-1962 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - History 165 - "Science in Western Civilization" - first semester, Vol. I, 1953-1959 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - History 311; 312; 105a; 166, 1962-1966 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Society for the Humanities - fund raising, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Society for the Humanities, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Russian attitudes towards science, 1945-1949 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Goldwin Smith research account A72-4104 (old A72-8102), 1975-1977 (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - Reprint mailing list (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - History of Science Collection - Miss Ellen Wells -correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - History of Science - Ph.D., 1973 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - Graduate students, 1970-1976 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Professors-at-large - general, 1970-1977 (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - History Department, 1972-1974 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - History of Science Newsletter, 1974-1977 (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - History of Science Society (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Académie Internationale d'Histoire des Sciences (Box 32, Folder 42)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 32, Folder 43)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1970-1976 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1972-1974 33 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1972-1977 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1973-1975 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Society for the Humanities, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Organization of University Faculty, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Administration work for History 916 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Applicants for admission, 1963-1965 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Applicants for admission to the Ph.D. program, 1964, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Arts College curriculum (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Committee on University Broadcasting, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Campus unrest, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Candidates for Cornell post in History of Science, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Committee on the Graduate Center (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Completed rating sheets - temporary file, 1960-1961 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Cornell program in History of Science, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1961 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Deanship questions, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Council, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Graduate applications, 1954-1956 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Graduate program in History of Science (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - History Department, 1949-1958 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - History Department, 1964-1968 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - History 70, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - History Department Honors Program, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - History 165-166, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - History 165-166 (mimeographs, prelims, make-ups, maps, etc.), 1949-1950 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - History 165-166, 1950-1951 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - History 165-166, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - History 165-166, 1951-1953 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - History 165, Fall term, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - History 166 - Spring term, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - History 165-166 (Mr. Beale), 1953-1954 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - History 165-166 (Mr. Beale), 1954-1955 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - History 165-166, 1955-1956 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - History 165-166, 1948-1949 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - History 165 - Fall term, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - History 165 - Examinations, 1951-1963 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - History 166 - Examinations, 1955-1956 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - History 166, Spring, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - History of Science collections - Dorothy M. Schullian, 1962-1963 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - History Department - honors program, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - History 311-312, 1963-1969 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - History 444 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - History 467 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - History 911, 913, 916 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - History of Early Modern Science - seminar #665 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Library Fund 302 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - History 166 - outlines, short paper topics, examinations - taught by L.G. Wilson assisted by Miss R. Rappaport, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 49)
  - Humanities Council, 1957-1958 (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - International Society for the History of Ideas (Box 33, Folder 51)
  - Library statements, 1951-1953 (Box 33, Folder 52)
  - Library correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 33, Folder 53)
  - Library exhibits (Box 33, Folder 54)
  - National Science Foundation - Lavoisier grant, 1965-1966 (Box 33, Folder 55)
  - National Defense Education Act fellowships - Fall, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 56)
  - Nomination committee, 1957-1958 (Box 33, Folder 57)
  - History of Science for engineering students, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 58)
  - Faculty re-organization, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 59)
  - Report to the National Science Foundation Projects, 1964-1969 (Box 33, Folder 60)
  - Rhoda Rappaport, 1955-1962 (Box 33, Folder 61)
  - Job opportunities (Box 33, Folder 62)
  - Talk on the book - seminar, Oct. 1, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 63)
  - Radio talks, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 64)
  - Salary increments, 1948-1951 (Box 33, Folder 65)
  - John B. Woolf: Rise of Modern Europe - "The Frontiers of Knowledge", July 1950 (Box 33, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, July 1970 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1970 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1970 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1970 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1970 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1970 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, May 1971 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, June 1971 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, July 1971 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, May 1972 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, June 1972 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, July 1972 (Box 34, Folder 25-26)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, May 1973 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, June 1973 (Box 34, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, July 1973 (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, May 1974 (Box 34, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, June 1974 (Box 34, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, July 1974 (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1974 (Box 34, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, May 1975 (Box 34, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, June 1975 (Box 34, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, July 1975 (Box 34, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, May 1976 (Box 34, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, June 1976 (Box 34, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence, July 1976 (Box 34, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1976 (Box 34, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1977 (Box 34, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1977 (Box 34, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1977 (Box 34, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1977 (Box 34, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence, May 1977 (Box 34, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence, June 1977 (Box 34, Folder 85)
- Series XXXVI. Other
  - Henry Guerlac CV, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Henry Guerlac reprints, 1932-1986 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - John F. Fulton, 1942-1947 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Other reprints, 1941-1952 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Lavoisier article, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Foote Prints, vol. 46, no. 2, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Transactions of the American Philosophical Society, 1955, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Syracuse University holdings, Undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
- Series XXXVII. Unprocessed material
  - Unprocessed material (Box 35-39)